<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Dataviz.Shef RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Promoting and building community around data visualisation at the University of Sheffield.]]></description><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk</link><image><url>https://github.com/researchdata-sheffield/dataviz-hub2/blob/development/src/images/author/dataviz.png</url><title>Dataviz.Shef RSS Feed</title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk</link></image><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 05:34:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>1440</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Some Good Practice Guidelines]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/16/03/2021/Good-Practice-Guide/Index</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/16/03/2021/Good-Practice-Guide/Index</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gemma Ives]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Some good practice guidelines There is a lot of readily available advice to help us improve our plots and avoid common pitfalls. Seminal work from Edward Tufte and John Tukey are excellent places to look for guidance. 
As well as a plethora of modern examples including;  from Data to Viz ,  Cynthia Brewer&apos;s  work on colour, 
 Bang Wong&apos;s  points of view series for Nature Methods and of course, the work of  Jeffery Heer . With so much excellent advice out there, 
what I hope to do with this blog is synthesise some of the more common issues that may face you when creating data visualisations. I…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hosting Shiny Apps]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/01/03/2021/Hosting-Shiny-Apps</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/01/03/2021/Hosting-Shiny-Apps</guid><category><![CDATA[docs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dataviz Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Publish your apps We recommend registering for a  personal ShinyApps.io account  for hosting your Shiny apps. This allows you to host up to five public apps and allows for a certain number of  execution hours  per month. If you want to create more than five apps, need your app(s) to be password-protected or think you have or will exceed your execution hours quota then please get in touch via  helpdesk@sheffield.ac.uk.    Data governance You should not host Shiny apps on ShinyApps.io that rely on / include  sensitive data .  If you want to interactively explore sensitive data then contact…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Useful Resources for R]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/18/02/2021/Useful-Resources-for-R</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/18/02/2021/Useful-Resources-for-R</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[R]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Introduction Welcome to the  fourth blog post  of the series  Exploring packages in R . In this blog post you will see a summary of resources that you might find useful when using R.   (last updated on 18th Feb 2021).   I&apos;m looking for ...    Tutorials R Intro Learning R (video) R for Data Science: Lunchbreak Lessons (video) Learning the R Tidyverse (ideo) Blog / Articles RStudio FAQ R bloggers RStudio Blog Cheat sheets This  RStudio cheat sheets  website provided by RStudio contains cheat sheets for popular packages such as  ggplot2 ,  readr , and  Shiny , as well as cheat sheets (e.g…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Templates for Shiny applications]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/05/02/2021/Shiny-Template</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/05/02/2021/Shiny-Template</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shiny]]></category><category><![CDATA[Template]]></category><category><![CDATA[R]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gemma Ives, Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>With the Shiny package you can build interactive web applications using R script.
This tutorial will give you quick-start guide to help you begin to explore the versatile package and create your own applications as well as present some ready to use templates to help you to build your first Shiny app.  With the Shiny package installed you can start to develop your app.
The basic components of a shiny app are ui commands and server commands.
The ui commands make up the user facing part of the app, this is where users can declare inputs;
common inputs are listed in this   helpful widget gallery…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interactive Visualisations in R]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/27/01/2021/Interactive-Visualisations-In-R</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/27/01/2021/Interactive-Visualisations-In-R</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[R]]></category><category><![CDATA[Plotly]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shiny]]></category><category><![CDATA[Interactive]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Introduction Welcome to the  third blog post  of the series  Exploring packages in R . In this blog post we will explore some of the most popular packages in R for  Interactive Visualisations  and some of which you might have already noticed. Same as in the  previous blog post , I will be using the  Hadfield Green Roof 5-year dataset  and assume you already have some experience with R. You can find all the source code in  this Github repository . If you have any suggestions or want me to include any particular package feel free to  send me an email !   In the first two sections we will explore…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Data visualisation in c++ with computational models]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/25/01/2021/Morphologica</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/25/01/2021/Morphologica</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dataviz]]></category><category><![CDATA[C++]]></category><category><![CDATA[Interactive]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Seb James]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>In this blog post I&apos;m going to talk about data visualisation - making graphs - within c++ programs. I&apos;ll describe why you might want to do this and I&apos;ll try to justify why I&apos;ve spent a sizeable part of my time over the last couple of years developing graphing code in c++, rather than using Python or R like everyone else! The code I&apos;ll discuss is available at  https://github.com/ABRG-Models/morphologica .  Most of the academic blog posts and videos about data visualisation that I see refer to scripted languages like Python, R or MATLAB. These languages have the ability to render high quality…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Static Visualisations in R]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/20/01/2021/Static-Visualisations-In-R</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/20/01/2021/Static-Visualisations-In-R</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[R]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tidyverse]]></category><category><![CDATA[ggplot2]]></category><category><![CDATA[ggpubr]]></category><category><![CDATA[rgl]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lattice]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Introduction This is the  second blog post  of the series  Exploring packages in R . In this blog post we will explore some of the most popular packages in R for  Static Visualisations . Same as in the  previous blog post , I will be using the  Hadfield Green Roof 5-year dataset  and assume you already have some experience with R. You can find all the source code in  this Github repository . If you have any suggestions or want me to include any particular package feel free to  send me an email !   In the next section we will explore  ggplot2  - most popular package (according to download…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Data Processing for data visualisations in R]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/15/01/2021/Data-Processing-In-R</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/15/01/2021/Data-Processing-In-R</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[R]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tidyverse]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Some Introduction A major advantage of using R is that it is highly extensible, with a broad variety of packages designed for specific purposes available on the internet. An R package is a collection that puts together reusable functions, documentation describing these functions, and sometimes examples of datasets you can use out of the box. R itself includes a set of packages by default (typically called base packages), but there are many more fantastic packages online for you to investigate.   In this blog post we will explore some of the most popular packages in R for data processing when…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Moving from Excel to R]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/08/10/2020/moving-from-excel-to-r</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/08/10/2020/moving-from-excel-to-r</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Excel]]></category><category><![CDATA[R]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>There are a lot of things to learn when you make a transition from Excel to R, especially if you haven&apos;t touched programming languages before, 
everything can be overwhelming and frustrating. Hopefully this article will help you make a smooth transition by helping you install and set 
up relevant software, introduce some fundamental concepts of R, and give some examples R codes for most commonly used functions in Excel. If you want a 
more structured and detailed introduction to R, see following resources: If you have any suggestions please leave a comment below. Installation R is a popular…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft Excel Best Practices]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/30/09/2020/making-the-best-data-visualisations-in-excel</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/30/09/2020/making-the-best-data-visualisations-in-excel</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category><category><![CDATA[Excel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Best Practice]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>About Excel Microsoft Excel  is a well-known spreadsheet developed by Microsoft for platforms like Windows, macOS, and 
various mobile operating systems. Excel has been the industry standards for spreadsheet since 1993 and commonly used for 
calculations, creating graphs and charts, and pivoting tables. Microsoft built  Visual Basic for 
Application  (also known as VBA, derived from the programming language Visual Basic) into Excel that allows you to write scripts 
that automates repeated tasks, this script often called a  macro  - a series of instructions. Excel is easy to use with 
graphics…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Data Visualization’s Social Role]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/09/09/2020/data-visualizations-social-role</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/09/09/2020/data-visualizations-social-role</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social Factors]]></category><category><![CDATA[Effects]]></category><category><![CDATA[Effectiveness]]></category><category><![CDATA[Emotions]]></category><category><![CDATA[Engaging with Dataviz]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Helen Kennedy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>I have been researching the social role of data visualizations since 2013. I was working on a research project exploring 
how resource-poor public sector organisations were engaging with social media data, when I was struck by the visceral ways 
in which collaborators responded to visual representations of said data. Without taking the time to make sense of the data 
visualizations included in a report that the research team produced, one collaborator told us that he loved them, and he 
wanted more. This set me off on a path researching how people engage with data visualizations, the role that…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[With great power comes great responsibility - challenges in visualising data]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/05/09/2020/challenges-in-visualising-data</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/05/09/2020/challenges-in-visualising-data</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dataviz]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Rosie Higman]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>At  dataviz.shef.ac.uk  we generally focus on practical matters 
such as  how to create plots using Python  
and  best practice for choosing accessible colours for visualisation . 
But as researchers and practitioners we also need to be conscious of the wider social impact which 
can arise from visualising data and consider how to do so responsibly. This post was inspired 
by two recent Open Access publications; firstly,  Data Visualisation in Society  
(2020, Amsterdam University Press) edited by Sheffield’s  Professor Helen Kennedy  and  Professor Martin Engebretsen  
from the University of…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[D3.js for data visualisation]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/26/08/2020/D3js-for-data-visualisation</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/26/08/2020/D3js-for-data-visualisation</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[D3.js]]></category><category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category><category><![CDATA[Web]]></category><category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>What is D3.js D3  stands for  Data-Driven Document  and  D3.js  is known as an open-source Javascript 
library that is capable of producing  web-based interactive data visualisations  
in web browsers using  SVG ,  HTML  and  CSS . It is powerful and customisable yet has 
a  steep learning curve . If you are interested in online data visualisation or 
you have used many data visulisation libraries and want to DIY your own 
chart then give it a go!   Mike Bostock  - the main author of  D3.js  also created an online platform called 
 ObservableHQ  where you can host your javascript notebooks…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Visualising GM data with a Shiny dashboard]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/18/08/2020/GM</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/18/08/2020/GM</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shiny]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gemma Ives]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Introduction The genetic modification of crops could alleviate some of the demands placed on modern agriculture by a burgeoning world population, however, public acceptance of genetically modified organisms is low. A team of researchers from the University of Sheffield and Sheffield Hallam University (Mallinson  et al. , 2018) use a nationally representative sample of British adults to examine the public attitude towards GM-crops they go beyond traditional risk communication to investigate the socio-economic and demographic antecedents of opinion. You can read the published paper here…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Visualisation templates for Python]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/16/07/2020/python-visualisation-templates</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/16/07/2020/python-visualisation-templates</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Template]]></category><category><![CDATA[Python]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Learning path - Workflow]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/05/07/2020/LearningPath-Workflow</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/05/07/2020/LearningPath-Workflow</guid><category><![CDATA[docs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dataviz Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Learning path - Lab]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/04/07/2020/LearningPath-Lab</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/04/07/2020/LearningPath-Lab</guid><category><![CDATA[docs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dataviz Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deploy your dash app on Heroku platform]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/03/07/2020/Deploy-Your-Dash-App</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/03/07/2020/Deploy-Your-Dash-App</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category><category><![CDATA[Python]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dash]]></category><category><![CDATA[Web]]></category><category><![CDATA[Plotly]]></category><category><![CDATA[Deploy]]></category><category><![CDATA[Host]]></category><category><![CDATA[Heroku]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>It is exciting to see your beautiful dash app running locally, but it would be even more interesting if 
    others can interact with it over the web too!    1. Introduction This documentation assumes some prior knowledge of  Python  and HTML/CSS. A minimum of being able to install Python, packages, and be able to execute code should 
get you a example visualisation. If you need assistance with Python,  python.org  provides documentation and tutorials. In this documentation you will see the app that was built in  Dash tutorial  
deployed onto an online cloud platform -  Heroku , step by step…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Learning path - Introduction]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/03/07/2020/LearningPath-Introduction</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/03/07/2020/LearningPath-Introduction</guid><category><![CDATA[docs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dataviz Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hosting Jupyter Notebook]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/24/06/2020/host-jupyter-notebook</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/24/06/2020/host-jupyter-notebook</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jupyter Notebook]]></category><category><![CDATA[Host]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&quot;As a researcher I want to host Jupyter notebooks on the web for free so that people can access them over the internet.&quot; Introduction The Jupyter Notebook has become a very popluar web application for sharing and creating documents that contain 
live code, equations, visualisations and narrative text. This article put together a number of user-friendly 
pathways for running live, interactive Jupyter notebooks on the web, and documentation on how to use it. Binder Binder ( mybinder.org ) is a free and transparent public service offers an easy place to share 
computing environments to everyone…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interactive Notebook with Jupyter Widgets]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/16/06/2020/Jupyter-Widgets</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/16/06/2020/Jupyter-Widgets</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category><category><![CDATA[Python]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jupyter Widgets]]></category><category><![CDATA[Interactive]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&quot;Widgets are eventful python objects that have a representation in the browser, often as a control like a slider, textbox, etc. You can use widgets to build interactive GUIs 
for your notebooks. You can also use widgets to synchronize stateful and stateless information between Python and JavaScript.&quot;  - Jupyter widgets 1. Prerequsites This documentation follows from  &apos;Plots with Python&apos;  and 
assumes some prior knowledge of  Python . 
If you need assistance with Python,  python.org  provides 
documentation and tutorials. While this post introduces some basic elements of  ipywidgets , you…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dash: Layout and interactive]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/12/06/2020/dash-tutorial-2</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/12/06/2020/dash-tutorial-2</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category><category><![CDATA[Python]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dash]]></category><category><![CDATA[Web]]></category><category><![CDATA[Plotly]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&apos;Dash is a web application framework that provides pure Python abstraction around HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.&apos;    1. Prerequsites This documentation assumes some prior knowledge of  Python  and HTML/CSS. A minimum of being able to install Python, packages, and be able to execute code should 
get you a example visualisation. If you need assistance with Python,  python.org  provides documentation and tutorials. To follow this tutorial, it is best to use  JupyterLab  (2.0 or above). If you have time, 
read  Dash tutorial  and  Plot with Python  (you&apos;ll find some codes are coming from 
this post…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Simple data visualisations have become key to communicating about the COVID-19 pandemic, but we know little about their impact.]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/11/06/2020/simple-data-visualisations-have-become-key-to-communicating-about-the-COVID-19-pandemic</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/11/06/2020/simple-data-visualisations-have-become-key-to-communicating-about-the-COVID-19-pandemic</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Data Politics]]></category><category><![CDATA[COVID-19 virus (SARS-CoV-2)]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dataviz Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>If you had mentioned &apos;flattening the curve&apos; in 2019, chances are you would have been met with a blank stare. However, almost halfway through 2020, the language of data visualisation has become 
commonplace, and data visualisations are widely used to communicate about the pandemic to the public. However, as Helen Kennedy observes, their power to influence the public is still little understood. Credit: This post by Helen Kennedy was originally published on the  LSE Impact Blog  and is reproduced with their kind permission. There have never been so many line charts, bar charts and  choropleth…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Visualising data on the web with Python and Dash]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/04/06/2020/dash-tutorial</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/04/06/2020/dash-tutorial</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category><category><![CDATA[Python]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dash]]></category><category><![CDATA[Web]]></category><category><![CDATA[Plotly]]></category><category><![CDATA[Pandas]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jez Cope, Angus Taggart]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Dash  is a user interface library for creating analytical web applications. Those who use  Python  for data analysis, data exploration, visualization, 
modelling, instrument control, and reporting will find immediate use for  Dash . 1. Prerequsites This documentation assumes some prior knowledge of  Python . A minimum of being able to install Python, packages, and be able to execute code should get you a example visualisation.
If you need assistance with Python,  python.org  provides documentation and tutorials. The code in the snippets below is able to be copied verbatim into a file to create…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Visualising high risk areas for Covid-19 mortality]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/01/06/2020/visualising-high-risk-areas-for-covid-19-mortality</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/01/06/2020/visualising-high-risk-areas-for-covid-19-mortality</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Covid-19 mortality]]></category><category><![CDATA[Pandemic]]></category><category><![CDATA[Epidemiology]]></category><category><![CDATA[COVID-19 virus (SARS-CoV-2)]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dataviz Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Credit: This post was originally published by Neil Dymond-Green on the UK Data Service  Impact and Innovation Lab . By mid-March, emerging data from Northern Italy clearly showed that COVID-19 fatality rates were substantially higher in older age groups, particularly for men. 
Demographers  Ilya Kashnitsky  and  José Aburto  combined this data with data from 
EUROSTAT on the age-sex distribution of the population across European regions and published  a fascinating pre-print . This displayed the potential risk that each area faced from a large-scale COVID-19 outbreak. Areas with large…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Non-Numeric Data Visualisation]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/20/05/2020/Non-Numeric</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/20/05/2020/Non-Numeric</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dataviz]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gemma Ives]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Often when we think of data visualisations, we think of familiar plots like scatter plots, line graphs and bar charts; we think of numbers.
This can lead to the underutilisation of visualisation techniques in non-numerical research.
This is unfortunate as the benefits of visualisation are numerous and by no means exclusive to numerical data. When we visualise any set of data, many of their characteristics, such as patterns, clusters and anomalies can all become far more prominent, when compared with looking at the raw data.
In this respect, it is often more effective to tell a story with a…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Plots with Python]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/07/05/2020/dataviz-stats-2</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/07/05/2020/dataviz-stats-2</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Python]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Objectives Last article introduced some basic descriptive statistics such as measures of central tendency and measures of variation. In this article we will apply some measures to get a 
better understanding of selected datasets. Datasets we&apos;re using are Road Safety Data for accidents between 2016-2018, 
it can be download on  data.gov.uk . You&apos;ll probably want to look at  Variable lookup data guide  on the website as well, 
since some of variables are coded and represented by numbers. Setup One of quickest way to use python and packages is to install  Anaconda . 
Then go to  Environments  and…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using Colour in Data visualisation]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/06/05/2020/Colour-Schemes</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/06/05/2020/Colour-Schemes</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dataviz]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gemma Ives]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Statistics for Dataviz]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/02/05/2020/dataviz-stats-1</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/02/05/2020/dataviz-stats-1</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Descriptive statistics Statistics is the science of the collection, analysis, interpretation and presentation of data. Statistics can be applied to varies of areas such as education, biology, engineering, 
chemistry, psychology, sports etc. Statistics is mainly divided into  descriptive statistics  and  inferential statistics  (statistical inference).   Given a set of data, the usage of descriptive statistics is to summarise and describe the data. For example, Use specific numbers or charts to reflect the concentration and dispersion of data. 
The average score, the highest score, the…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Choosing Between Common Charts]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/06/04/2020/chart-choice</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/06/04/2020/chart-choice</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dataviz]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gemma Ives]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Data Visualisation]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/22/03/2020/datavizhub-guide</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/22/03/2020/datavizhub-guide</guid><category><![CDATA[docs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dataviz Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Contribute blog posts]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/22/03/2020/contribute-blog-post</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/docs/22/03/2020/contribute-blog-post</guid><category><![CDATA[docs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yu Liang Weng]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Introduction (UPDATED on 21 Apr 2021) This is a template for blog posts. This website is built from  Gatsby  framework and the way of styling is slightly different from HTML/CSS. 
You can write posts use  markdown  or/and HTML/CSS. A copy of this blog file is available  here . This article will guide you to setup a development environment, relevant steps for produce a blog post, and introduce 
you to useful syntax for styling the blog post and adding resources such as images, videos, and codes. 
You can also use Google Docs to write a post then  share  the link with us, we will take care of…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Urban Observatories hackathon]]></title><link>https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/28/02/2020/Urban-Observatories-hackathon</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dataviz.shef.ac.uk/blog/28/02/2020/Urban-Observatories-hackathon</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Events]]></category><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><category><![CDATA[Data Engineering]]></category><category><![CDATA[Data Analytics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Research & Innovation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Urban Observatory]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Heffer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>This post was originally posted on  Research &amp; Innovation blog . In February, The University of Sheffield hosted a three-day hackathon, an intensive collaborative software development event, organised by 
the  Data &amp; Analytics Facility for National Infrastructure  (DAFNI). The event aimed to begin tackling the 
complex challenges involved in coordinating analytics using data from urban observatories across the UK. DAFNI provides an analytics platform to enable innovative data analysis solutions 
for infrastructure research. An urban observatory is a network of sensors capturing atmospheric and…</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>